Bryan Stevens

Hi there! I am a highly skilled and motivated professional with over 3 years of experience in the tech industry. I have a strong background in software development and project management, and I am always looking for new challenges and opportunities to grow and learn

Experience

VuSpex - Software Engineer

June 2021 – Present

- Utilized software engineering expertise to develop products throughout the software lifecycle
- Reengineered native android and iOS mobiles apps using React Native
- Took responsibility of project management for company projects,
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop requirement guidelines, communicate needs and timelines

VuSpex - Junior Software Developer

May 2020 - June 2021

- Demonstrated expertise in translating client specific needs into easy to understand software solutions
- Proficiently troubleshot simple and complex technological issues across varying tech stacks
- Performed a key role in the development lifecycle of multiple products

StreamGuys - Junior Software Developer

September 2019 – May 2020

- Modified HTML, Javascript and css to optimize page performance
- Documented all supported systems to effectively train new and existing customers
- Provided prompt solutions and proactive troubleshooting to resolve subtle and complex issues

Projects

- (2021) <u>VuSpex GO: React Native OpenTok Geolocation Services:</u> Developed as a cross platform, single code base solution to replace VuSpex' existing iOS & android mobile apps. The app leverages various technologies from webRTC to gps allowing contractors, field agents, and permit applicants to conduct virtual inspections, create field reports to send to the inspector, and schedule face-to-face or virtual inspections.
- (2020) <u>ELevel+: React Native React N React Native Bluetooth LE:</u> Developed by myself and 2 others as part of a contract; the app connects and communicates with AccuAir's bluetooth module to receive, display and update real time height and position indicators as well as a handful of diagnostic feedback. Core to the app is this ability to update the 4 pieces of AccuAir's firmware stack through a chunked OTA update process.
- (2016) <u>Bitcoin Faucet: Objective-C:</u> The app utilized multiple ad networks to mediate advertisements; that coupled with persistent timestamps, small amounts of a Bitcoin were dished out to users for viewing ads. The app was live for several months with over 4.2K total downloads and over 230,000 sessions.

Education

Fullstack Academy of Code

October 2018 – February 2019

- Nationally-ranked software engineering bootcamp with a 9% acceptance rate
- Studied Object-Oriented Design, asynchronous programming and software design
- Extensively practiced pair-programming pairing with all other 28 students individually

Technical Skills

Advanced: React, React Native, NodeJS, Git, Javascript, Typescript, Swift, Objective-C, Java, SQL, PostGres **Knowledgeable**: AWS, GraphQL, NoSQL, Redux, Jest, C#, PHP, Angular